Curtis J. Jochen

12628 Copperas, Ln Richmond, Virginia 23233 (406) 471-1679 | Curtis. Jochen@gmail.com

github.com/Cjochen2 | | www.linkedin.com/in/curtisjochen/ | | https://cjochen2.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Hard-working, driven Software Developer with a focus in Full Stack-Web Development. Extensive experience in client facing roles helping resolve complex problems while being mindful of budget and deadlines. Strong communication and leadership skills from both working in and leading teams through fast pace production driven environments. Obtained University of Richmond's Full Stack Web Development Certification with an A average.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Proficient in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, VS Code, jQuery, Bootstrap and MS Office
- · Experience with React as well as state management resources like React-Redux, React-Context API, and React Hooks
- · Database MySQL and Mongo DB
- · Node.js Express, Security and Session Storage, User Authentication
- · Effective command of written and verbal communication
- · Experience in client-facing roles
- · Self-motivated professional with strong work ethic and ability to see tasks through to completion

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Program

Richmond, Virginia
October 2019

University of Richmond

- · Built front-end of applications from scratch as well as with ready-made frameworks using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars, and React
- · Designed CLI applications utilizing Express, Node, and MySQL
- · Worked in agile groups of 3 to 4 to design and build Full Stack Web Applications utilizing the MERN Stack
- · Designed and Developed full stack single page web applications with RESTful routes and AJAX methods
- · Learned about and worked through the entire development cycle of complex projects in both independent and collaborative settings

Non-Destructive Testing Certificate of Applied Science

Flathead Valley Community College

Kalispell, Montana December 2014

PROJECTS

Conway's Game of Life

React Hooks application recreating Conway's Game of Life

- · Utilizes Hooks for state management and updates
- · Structured with only functional components
- · Complex Logic based on the Game of Life rules, rules tell React which games to light up and grey out
- · Zero-Player game with user interaction coming mostly from the use of buttons

Try the App:

https://cjochen2.github.io/Conways-Game-of-Life-Tutorial-React/

Code Repo:

https://github.com/Cjochen2/Conways-Game-of-Life-Tutorial-React

Trivia Game

Dynamically created trivia game utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery

- Application dynamically generates HTML using jQuery
- Picks 5 random questions from an array and one static question out of an array with multiple choice answers
- Checks users answers against correct answers and returns a total score output.
- Application can be reset without refreshing the page

Try the App:

https://cjochen2.github.io/TriviaGame/

Code Repo:

https://github.com/Cjochen2/Conways-Game-of-Life-Tutorial-React

GifTastic

Uses Giphy API call to return 10 GIFs based on the button selected by the user

- Application makes a dynamic AJAX call to the Giphy API
- User can create a custom button to return GIFs with
- Application limits the number of GIFs to 10 and displays each one's rating
- GIFs render in a still state and can be activated and deactivated on click

Try the App:

https://cjochen2.github.io/GifTastic/

Code Repo:

https://github.com/Cjochen2/GifTastic

EXPERIENCE

Applied Technical Services

Non-Destructive Testing Technician

Richmond, Virginia January 2015 – Current

- · Driving long-term projects to completion while managing strict deadlines and budgets
- · Lead point of contact with the customer, responsible for ensuring overall client satisfaction and clear communication
- · Provide expertise to the client on Applied Technical Services solutions and how to utilize them
- · Directly supervise a 10+ member team, making complex decisions on best utilizing team skills to complete projects under
- · Mentor and train junior employees to increase their working knowledge in Advanced Ultrasonic Testing techniques, applications, limitations, material sensitivity and equipment calibration

Best Buy Kalispell, Montana

Mobile Sales Rep

November 2013 – December 2014

- · Understanding customer's technical needs and providing them with the appropriate solution
- · Consistently a top performer in a production-oriented environment
- · Leverage analytical and problem-solving skills to proactively improve customer service process

Montana Fire Eureka, Montana May 2013 - November 2014

Wildland Firefighter

- · Focus for extended periods of time to ensure safety in a constantly changing and dangerous environment
- · Work effectively in a team-oriented environment to ensure achievement of daily and overall objectives
- · Maintain an updated knowledge of safety guidelines, firefighting techniques, treatment protocols and quality assurance procedures